That spring, we were all
watching the events of space
那个春天,我们都在观察空间运动
and wondering what
the final effect would be.
以便能够看到最后的效应
Astronomers argued over theory
天文学家们正在对原理进行辩论
while engineers got
pretty excited about variables
and magnetic fields.
同时工程师们对变数和磁场感到很兴奋
Mystics predicted earthquakes
神秘主义者对地震进行了预测
and the end of life
as we knew it.
生命的尽头就如我们所知
When the effect came
it was almost unnoticed
效应发生时,几乎没法注意到
because it happened
to such a small
and insignificant form of life.
因为它会在这么微不足道的
小生命体上表现出来
One biologist,
an English man, Ernest Hubbs
一位生物学家,一个英国人,
欧内斯特·哈布斯
saw something, got nervous
and started investigating.
发现某些现象后,他焦虑起来,
并开始着手调查
While I was playing around with
number theory at the university
当我在大学里对数论提不起劲时
Hubbs was already on
to something.
哈布斯已经在做些什么了
Ordinary ants
of different species
不同品种的普通的蚂蚁们
were doing things
ants don't do.
正在做些蚂蚁不会做的事
Meeting, communicating.
会谈,交流
Apparently making decisions.
似乎是在作出决定
By summer the rest of the world
had moved on to other things
夏天到了,其他人已把注意力
转移到别的东西上面去了
but Hubbs kept making notes.
但哈布斯一直在记笔记
While the threat grew.
同时威胁也在增长
Only fragments
of what he knew got out
他发现的一些片段
he kept most of it to himself.
大部分都被他藏起来了
So when I got into it,
I didn't know a damn thing.
所以当我加入时,
我什么鬼情况都不了解
"Memorandum to Alf
Launder Smith"
阿尔夫·朗德·史密斯的技术备忘录
"Secretary,
National Science Foundation"
助理,国家科学基金会
"Committee on
biological controls. "
生物管理委员会
"From E.D. Hubbs, Senior Fellow
Coronado Institute"
E·D·哈布斯,科罗拉多学院高级研究员
"Subject - Biological imbalance
in an upland Arizona Valley. "
研究项目 亚利桑那州生物不平衡现象
"Facts on hand -
traditional antagonisms,"
事实上是因为在几种蚂蚁之间,
"amongst several ants species
have come to a dramatic halt. "
传统的对立行为出现了戏剧性的停止
"At the same time there has
been an apparent disappearance"
"of those insects
which prey on ants"
同时,那些以蚂蚁为食的
昆虫明显地消失了
"specifically mantises,
beetles,
"millipedes and spiders. "
特别是蟑螂,甲壳虫,千足虫和蜘蛛
"If these conditions persist
they must inevitably"
如果以上条件继续存在的话,它们一定
"lead to increases
in ant population. "
是为了增加蚂蚁的数量
"Proposal - An immediate
full scale attack"
建议 对威胁着其他生命体的
"on the threat of biological
imbalance to other life forms"
生物不平衡现象
展开一次直接的全面进攻
"in the subject area. "
在主题范围内
"Mode of operation -
an experiment station"
操作方式
建立一座实验站
"to be built and maintained
with equipment"
"sophisticated enough
to control the problem"
"and any potential
consequences. "
并配备足够多的精密仪器
以控制问题和潜在的后果
"Personnel - one senior
scientist, myself. "
成员 一个高级科学家,我
"Plus one associate"
加上一个助理
"a qualified information
specialist"
"with cryptological
background. "
一个有密码学背景的
合格的信息专员
"In this connection
I have been impressed"
"with the recent work
of J. R. Lesko"
"at the naval under sea
centre of San Diego. "
因为这种关系，我对J·R·莱斯科最近在
圣迭戈海洋中心的船上的工作印象很深刻
"Location of installation -"
安装位置
"it is suggested
the experiment station"
"be placed in the locale"
"of the most recently observed
phenomena. "
建议把实验站设立在
最近观察到过现象的地区
"Conclusions and
recommendations -"
结论与建议
"speed is of the essence. "
速度是关键因素
This is the place.
就是这地方
This is it.
就这儿了
No bodies I hope.
我希望这里没人
The population moved itself out
some days ago.
人们在前些日子已自行搬迁出去了
We've got some pretty powerful
friends.
我们得到了些很有力的朋友
Just another
desert development
which did not develop.
不过是另一个未完全沙漠化的沙漠
You did your major work
applying game theory to
the language of killer whales.
你做了应用虎鲸语言的
博弈论的主要工作
Well, it seemed cheaper
than applying it to real air.
好吧,看起来比将其应用于
真正的空气更为廉价
Did you actually succeed
in making positive contact
with the whales?
你真的成功跟鲸鱼积极地接触过么?
Only with
the emotionally disturbed.
这只对精神紊乱的有用
How were you able
to determine that?
你是怎么确定的?
We talked.
我们谈过了
Is that a joke?
那只是个玩笑吗?
Look, I'm sorry, I'm strictly
a pencil and paper guy
听着,我很抱歉,
我是个对记录很严格的人
I wouldn't know the front end
of a whale
我不知道鲸鱼的前端...
from...
A hole in the ground.
来自...地坑
I know that game's
your business, James,
我知道那游戏是你的主意,詹姆斯
you play them very well.
That's why you're here.
你把他们刷得团团转,
所以你被派到了这
But this is a serious game.
但这是个很严肃的游戏
Well, that's the best kind,
isn't it?
好吧,那是最棒的,不是吗?
Wednesday, three o'clock,
星期三,三点
further discoveries
this afternoon
on a nearby farm.
今天下午在附近的农场
有了更多的发现
To be added to those
observed earlier.
已经添加到先前所观察到的信息
I might have pointed them out
to Lesko.
我也许得向莱斯科点明出来
But it would be better to
let him learn at his own pace.
但让他按自己的步调学习
也许会更好一些
There are certain
equatorial ants
这里确实有些赤道的蚂蚁
that would attack anything -
insects, mammals -
也许会攻击一些...
昆虫,哺乳动物...
anything at all that threatens
their food supply.
所有威胁到它们食物供给的生物
The smell
triggers their behavior.
味道引起了它们的行动
Yeah.
对
They are picky eaters.
它们是会挑食的
Now this thing here.
现在在这的这玩意儿
You see what we're doing,
你看到我们在做什么
we're running lines
from these fuel tanks
我们要利用这些油罐
and if those ants get over
that water trap
如果那些蚂蚁克服了水陷阱
we're gonna set fire
to this here ditch
我们就会在这壕沟里放火
and watch 'em all burn.
然后看着它们全部烧光
What do you think?
你觉得呢?
Done a lot of good work.
工作完成得不错
I'd say they started pulling out
three, four weeks ago
我会说它们从三、四个星期前
就已经开始撤出了
a couple of families at a time.
每次两个家族
What else?
还有呢?
That's about the size of it.
它的尺寸
I guess it must have been
some kind of infestation
我猜这一定是某种类型的群袭
but ... Well, I couldn't say
for sure.
但是...好吧,我不能确定
Maybe the heat
got too much for 'em.
也许对它们来说太热了
There's a collapsed house
down there.
那下面有栋倒塌了的房子
Well, I wouldn't know
about that.
好吧,我并不知道它
I didn't really get to know
those people
我真的不了解这些人...
they were...
They were city folk mainly.
他们是...他们主要是城里人
Tell me about the towers.
跟我说说楼塔吧
Don't know,
wasn't there.
不知道,本来没有的
Of course
it's been a dry year.
当然,这里总是旱年
You know we do get ants
in dry years.
你知道我们在旱年观察蚂蚁
Hmm.
嗯
I talked to an entomologist
up at the state department
of agriculture at one time
我有一次在国家农业部时,
和一个昆虫学家说过
he said these things
were cyclical.
他说这些东西是环状的
They weren't talking about
those ants.
他们并不是在讨论那些蚂蚁
Mildred, come on out here.
米尔维,过来这里
That's alright.
It isn't alright.
-没事的 -没事才怪
These people will think
I've got you chained up
in there.
这些人会以为,
我把你锁进里面去了
These gentlemen are from
the university,
这些来自大学的绅士们,
they're gonna develop
a new spray for those ants.
他们打算给那些蚂蚁弄些新的装饰
You know what I think.
你知道我是怎么想的
Ha! You know if she didn't have
something to worry about,
哈!你知道如果她
没什么需要担心的
she wouldn't know what to do
with herself.
她就不会知道自己应何去何从了
I'm afraid you're gonna have to
leave for a few days
恐怕你得离开几天
Mr. Eldridge.
埃尔德里奇先生
Evacuation?
撤离?
Look I...
Mr. Eldridge.
听着,我...
埃尔德里奇先生
I- I-I don't understand this.
It's for your own protection.
-我,我,我无法理解,
-这是为了你的安全
Evacuation?
What's this all about anyway?
撤离?这到底是怎么回事?
Why this isn't right.
They can't just push us off-
这为什么不是对的,
他们不能这么让我们离开...
didn't you hear
what the man said?
你没听到那男的说什么吗?
It's for our protection.
这是为了我们的安全
When do they get
their farm back?
他们打算几时把农场收回来?
That depends.
由他们决定
Friday, eight o'clock,
星期五,八点
the zone should now be clear
of population,
现在该地区的人口应该被清走了
we can proceed
with the next step.
我们可以继续下一步了
The facility is completely
self contained,
设施很齐全,
except for
a primary power source
除了没有主电源
and the generator in our trucks
supplies this,
所以由我们卡车里的
发电机来供电
the experiment has begun.
实验开始了
What's wrong?
怎么回事?
Well, I guess they're not ready
to play yet.
呃,我猜它们还没准备好要运行
Dr. Hubbs,
哈布斯博士
there's already been
a twelve day over run
这里已经运行十二天了
which averages out at 36%
when projected over the course
of the total program.
在总计划中,
平均达到了36%
The controller would like
to get the final figure
before the fiscal period ends
on the 14th.
管理人应该很想在14号
财务期间结束之前拿到终值
Shall we put you down
for one more week?
要我们把你放下去一个多星期吗?
I'm sorry,
this is not a precise business.
我很抱歉,这不是一笔精确的交易
Well, can you give us
an estimate?
好吧,你能给我们大概时间吗?
We cannot study the ants
until they make an appearance.
我们得等到蚂蚁出现时才能研究它们
Can we put you down
for ten more days?
我们能把你放下去十天吗?
This is not
a controlled experiment,
这不是一个对照实验,
in our judgment another
occurrence in this area
is highly probable.
依我们判断,这地方很有可能
再次发生事件
But we cannot command
the ants to appear.
但我们没法命令蚂蚁出现
Well is there something
you could do to hurry them up?
好吧,你能不能让它们赶紧上来?
We have been thinking
about that.
我们一直在想办法
You know, of course,
there is concern
over possible outbreaks
in other areas?
你知道,当然,是对其它地区
有可能爆发这件事感到忧虑?
Ah, I share that concern.
啊,我分享了那份顾虑了
My associate, Mr. Lesko,
has something to say.
我的助手,莱斯科先生,有话要说
Listen, I want you
to do me a favor -
听着,我要你帮我个忙...
I want you to call Miss Dobson,
d-o-b-s-o-n.
我要你打电话给多布森小姐,
D-O-B-S-O-N
6-6-2-0-7-9-9 in Los Angeles.
洛杉矶的6-6-2-0-7-9-9
Tell her not to take
the plane to Vegas on thursday.
告诉她星期四别乘飞机去维加斯
Tell her it'll be
a couple more weeks and...
告诉她要花两个多星期...
She'll hear from me, okay?
她会收到的,好吧?
Did you say
a couple of weeks?
你是不是说过两个星期?
That's right.
是的
Mr. Lesko, that's not
going to be possible,
accord-
莱斯科先生,那是不可能的事,
按照...
let's see some activity.
我们来看看它们活跃的时刻吧
Hi, there?
嗨,那里是?
Clete!
克里特!
Ants.
蚂蚁
They got the horse,
clete, light the fire.
它们逮到那马了,克里特,点火
Kendra. Oh, my god.
坎多拉,哦,我的天呐
Grandpa,
can't you something?
爷爷,您就不能做点什么吗?
Oh, my god.
哦,我的天呐
Clete, get over here.
克里特,去那边
Can't you do something?
您就不能做点什么吗?
Give me the gun.
把枪给我
No, no, no.
Let me go.
不,不,不,放开我
Clete, get her in the house,
get her in the house.
克里特,把她带到屋子里去,
把她带进去
Don't kill him.
别杀了他
All set?
准备好了吗?
Keep down now.
That's right. Hang on.
继续下去,就这样,坚持下去
Now this is really interesting.
现在这真的很有趣
You see what I do is I get to
the parameters of the problem
by breaking down the movement of
a vector of a single anthill.
你看到我所做的就是通过破坏蚁丘的
矢量运动来获取这个问题的各方面情况
Now, I don't know what
they're doing, I don't care,
现在,我不知道它们
在做什么,我不在乎
I'm just breaking down
their simple basic move.
我只负责破坏它们简单的基本动作
Stop, go.
停下,快走
Turn,
转弯,
duration.
That's it period, okay?
继续,到此为止,行吗?
Now I take my ant signals,
现在我带着我的蚂蚁信号
I run them through
the digitizer,
我通过数字化仪来运行它们
I record them on tape,
我用磁带来记录它们
I write them down and
I search for a correlation
between what they say
and what they do.
我把它们记下来并搜索
它们所说所做之间的相关性
Now assumption.
现在假设
What we're seeing and hearing
are commands
being directed
at the central mass.
我们所看到所听过的东西是
一直是核心人群所发出的命令
They warned us.
它们警告过我们
Relax.
放松点
I forgot to turn out the light.
我忘了关灯了
Stop! Cut it out!
What's the matter?
停下!快切断!
怎么回事?
Cut it out!
快切断!
Come back here.
回来
Goddamn it, will you sit...
该死的,你能坐下...
They're all over the place.
它们到处都是
Clete, take care of the women.
Get some help.
克里特,照顾女士们,去寻求帮助
Now I make various adjustments,
现在我在做各种调整,
make up for time lag
and a couple of other things
弥补滞后的和几样东西的时间
don't worry about it.
别担心
Then I come up with...
然后我想出办法...
Ha, are you ready for this?
哈,你准备好了吗?
I come up with a positive
correlation on the order of 80%
between this little squiggle
我想到了在这些小波形曲线
之间大概有80%的正相关
and the command we commonly
know as stop.
这些命令的停止方式
和我们平常所知道的一样
And a positive correlation
between that little squiggle
and go.
还有那波形曲线之间的正相关和
And that means
these little mothers
talk to each other.
这表示这帮小混蛋会互相交流
Now I think if I-
hey, the lights.
现在,我认为如果我...
嘿,灯光
They've got into
the generator. Don't move,
它们到发电机里去了,别动
the back up unit
cuts in automatically.
备份单元会自动切割
I'm going to counter
with 100% yellow.
我要用100%的
黄色化学药品来反击它们
You're letting some get away.
你要赶跑那些东西
Maybe they've learnt something.
也许它们已经学到了些什么
Come over here, James,
到这儿来,詹姆斯,
this is really fascinating.
这真是迷人
People are dead
back there.
人都死了,回来
Yes, a tragedy.
是啊,真是个悲剧
I don't understand it,
they accepted the order,
我不明白,它们已经接受命令了
why should they come here?
为什么还要到这来?
Irrational behavior,
very sad.
不合理的行为,很惨烈
Now just look at this, James.
现在来看看这个,詹姆斯
Consider the execution
of this maneuver,
in order to explode
the generator,
考虑一下执行这个动作的目的,
为了探索发电机,
they had to create
a living chain-
它们不得不制造一个活的...
listen, Hubbs, those people
are dead, don't you understand?
听着,哈布斯,那些人死了,
你还不明白吗?
People get killed sometimes.
人们有时候也会被杀
I think this yellow
should hold it's potency
for three or four days.
我想这些黄色化学试剂
在三四天内应该能继续发挥效力
We can
start collecting now.
我们现在能开始收集了
Little sons of bitches.
该死的小婊子
No, no, no.
不,不,不
They're not individuals,
they are individual cells.
它们不是个体,它们是个体细胞
Tiny functioning parts
of the whole.
整体中有着
微小的功能的部分
Think of a society, james,
with perfect harmony,
perfect altruism
and self sacrifice,
想想社会,詹姆斯,和谐、
完全利他且自我牺牲、
perfect division of labor,
organized for preordained roles.
完善的分工、注定被组织的角色
Think of the building,
elaborate and complex structures
according to plans
that they know nothing of,
想想建筑物,那是它们所
不知道的计划中的复杂结构,
but can execute perfectly.
但还是能够完美的执行
Think of their ability to evolve
and adapt
in ways that are so beautiful,
想想它们发展和适应的能力,
真是美丽极了
and still so unknown
and all contained
in one simple form.
而且还是如此的神秘,这些
全都包含在一个简单的形式内
So defenseless in the individual,
and so powerful in the mass.
所以个体不堪一击,
总体却是如此强大
Well...
好吧...
Let's begin with
the first behavioral series,
让我们从第一个
行为系列开始吧
heat, cold, isolations,starvation,
slow pressure,and threat.
热,冷,隔离,绝食,
舒缓压力,还有恐吓
Mantises prey on ants,
as you know.
螳螂捕食蚂蚁,你知道的
Now if-
现在,如果...
if you're still with us, James.
如果她还跟着我们,詹姆斯
When are we gonna
get her out of here?
我们要几时把她送出去?
That's going to be
a little difficult, I'm afraid.
恐怕那会变得有点儿困难
Um... turn on the microphone,
please?
呃...能请你打开我的话筒吗?
Call in and have them send out
a helicopter.
叫他们派一架直升机过来
I'm afraid the bureaucrats
will be rather unhappy
with all of our casualties.
恐怕官僚主义者们会对我们的
伤亡人数感到很不满意
Now...
现在...
Mantises,
at this end of the maze,
the ants are at the other.
螳螂们,就在迷宫的尽头,
而蚂蚁们在另一头
What are we gonna do
with the girl?
我们要怎么处理那女孩?
What is your concern with her?
你和她有什么关系?
She's in shock,
we can't just... she's a kid.
她处于震惊之中,
我们不能...她还是个孩子
Don't shout.
别大喊大叫
This is a problem that
will have to be dealt with
over the next few days
until we're finished.
这个问题会在我们
在几天内完成后被解决
If you won't call the base,
I will.
你不呼叫基地的话,那我来
I'm very much afraid that that
will end our mission.
我很担心我们的任务会结束
Screw our mission.
让那任务见鬼去吧
I've finished eating.
我已经吃完了
You know,
I don't know your name.
你知道的,我不知道你的名字
Oh, Kendra.
I'm Jim.
哦,坎多拉,我是吉姆
That's Dr. Hubbs.
那是哈布斯博士
Come in, come on.
进来,快点
You sort of had a close call
out there, didn't you?
你在外面有个
亲切的称呼,不是吗?
How do you feel?
Well, I'm ready to go home now.
你感觉怎样?
很好,我准备好回家去了
Um... I'll send
a message today.
呃...我今天会发一条信息
Somebody will come along
and pick you up tomorrow,
明天会有人过来并把你接走
if that's convenient.
如果方便的话
They killed my horse.
它们杀了我的马
Kendra, I'm sorry.
坎多拉,我很抱歉
Kendra!
坎多拉!
Stop it, stop it.
住手,快住手
Back away.
走开
Don't touch anything.
什么也别碰
It's alright.
没事了
That should do it.
就该这么做
You've been bitten.
你被咬了
So we thought if you
knocked down one of the towers,
所以我们认为如果你把
其中一个塔给击毁的话,
taking proper precautions
of course,
当然要采取些适当的预防措施
you might get
an interesting reaction.
你可能会收到些有趣的反应
We'll consider it.
我们会确认的
Just an idea doctor.
Appreciated.
只不过是个主意,博士
非常感谢
Oh, one other thing.
Yes?
喔,还有一件事
什么事?
We got a report about a family
in your vicinity;
我们收到了关于
你附近的一家子的报告
you haven't contacted
any civilians, have you?
你没有接触任何平民,对吗?
No.
是的
Monday, 2:00 a. m.
星期一,上午两点
Lesko continues
to make progress,
莱斯科继续取得进展,
deciphering the ant language
from the tapes recorded
during the first skirmish.
从第一次冲突时所记录的磁带上
破译蚂蚁的语言
If he maintains this pace,
如果他要保住这地方,
we should be ready
for their next move.
我们就该为它们的
下一步行动做准备
It's a rather crude language,
这是种相当粗俗的语言,
I think if I keep building up
my library of sound words
我想如果我继续建立
我的声音数据库的话
I might even...
我甚至可能会...
Strike up a conversation
with them.
开始和它们对话
Of course then the ants
would have to come back.
当然在那之后
那些蚂蚁们会回来
We'd have to be here
for a while.
我们得在这里等会儿
When's the helicopter coming?
直升机什么时候到?
Oh, it'll be here.
喔,会过来的
I'm sorry about that.
Oh, not your fault.
-我对那感到很抱歉
-哦,这不怪你
Listen, you really wanna see
something?
听着,你真的想看到些什么吗?
Another way of visualizing
their signals.
使它们的信号
可视化的另一种方式
Watch this.
看看这个
I don't have the faintest idea
what it means.
我对这些的意义一无所知
Hey?
嘿?
Remember me?
还记得我吗?
Oh, y-y-yeah!
噢,耶!
How do you feel?
你感觉怎样?
Oh... Better.
That's good.
-哦...好些了
-那就好
H- h-how is um...
我是怎么...
dr. hubbs?
Yeah.
-哈布斯博士？
-是的
Oh, he'll survive.
哦,他会活下来的
I'm really sorry about that I...
我对那感到很抱歉...
Listen, if I were you
I'd have popped those ants
pretty good myself.
听着,换作我是你,
我会好好的逮住那些蚂蚁
You know
you've got a mean swing.
你知道的,
你已经动摇了
Well, the main thing is
you're alright.
好吧,主要就是你一切安好
We'll get you out of here today.
我们今天会把你送出去
What's the matter?
怎么回事?
Don't tell me
you like this place?
别告诉我你喜欢这地方?
My grandparents are dead,
aren't they?
我祖父母都死了,不是吗?
Yeah, they are.
对,是的
What?
Don't you have parents?
什么?你父母已经不在了?
Well, you must be hungry.
好吧,你一定饿了
Come on,
I'll get you some breakfast.
好了,我会给你些早餐的
Okay.
好吧
Follow me through
the hardware department.
在硬件部时要紧跟着我
Can I ask you a question?
Yeah, sure, go ahead.
-我能问你个问题吗?
-好的,请便,继续
What do you do here?
你们在这里做什么?
Just a little research into
statistical probabilities.
只是个小小的概率统计调查
Really?
It must be interesting.
真的?那一定很有趣
Well, we've got powdered eggs,
powdered milk,
powdered juice,
dehydrated bacon,
just like home.
好吧,我们有鸡蛋,奶粉,果汁,
脱水的培根,就像在家里一样
James?
詹姆斯?
Are you alright?
Oh, yeah.
-你还好吗?
-喔,是的
See you in a little while.
Okay.
-稍会儿见
-好的
Good morningJames.
早安,詹姆斯
As you can see
we're under siege.
如你所见,我们被包围了
What the hell's that?
那该死的是什么?
It's more than
reflected sunlight.
它反射了更多的日光
Our temperature is already up
five degrees.
我们的温度
已经升了5华氏度了
There's another
interesting detail.
那又是个有趣的细节
How do you suppose those ants
managed to build
on a poisonous strip where they
absolutely cannot live?
你对那些蚂蚁建立于它们完全
无法生存的地方有什么看法?
Did you say five degrees?
Hmm.
-你说了是5华氏度吧?
-呃
In an hour and a half.
在一个半小时内
And of course the sun's
not yet at full strength.
当然阳光还没足够强
Now watch this.
An hour and a half?
-现在来看看这个
-这也是在一个半钟头内?
Oh, you must watch this,
this is fascinating, there.
哦,你一定要看看这个,
非常迷人,这里
Beautiful adaptation,
isn't it?
漂亮的适应能力,不是吗?
We challenge with
yellow chemistry,
我们用
黄色的化学试剂挑衅它们,
they respond with
yellow creatures.
它们以黄色的生物回报我们
We're gonna fry in here.
我们会在这被煎熟了
Question,
what do they want?
问题,它们想要什么?
What are their goals?
They have no goals.
-它们的目的是?
-它们没有目的
Well, you saw how
they disabled the truck.
好吧,你看到了它们
是怎么把卡车给废了的
Listen, Hubbs,
I came down here
to get in a couple of weeks
of science in the sun,
听着,哈布斯,我来这里是为了
在太阳底下进行两周的实验
I did not sign up for a war
against a bunch of goddamn ants.
我不是为了和一堆该死的蚂蚁开战
And furthermore, why the hell
did you leave the truck
out there in the first place?
此外,你当初为什么他妈的
把卡车留在了外面?
Bait.
那是诱饵
Bait?
诱饵?
Well, I had to get them
to attack us, didn't I?
是的,我必须让它们攻击我们,不是吗?
They're rather intelligent,
you know.
它们极其聪明,你知道的
I thought you'd observed that
geometric pattern in the field?
我以为你会研究
田地上的几何图形
You mean you saw it?
你是说你看到了?
Of course I did.
当然了
Why didn't you say something?
Why didn't you?
你为什么什么也不说?为什么?
Well, I didn't think you were
smart enough to appreciate it.
我不认为你会够聪明地来欣赏它们
With all your high class
bug talk.
你那些高级的错误的谈话
I was afraid that
you'd be terrified and run away,
我怕你会害怕然后跑开,
and I need you.
但我需要你
Well, you're right about that.
When's the helicopter coming?
好吧,你是对的,
直升机要什么时候到?
James,
we are faced with a power
that has appeared
and is exerting itself.
詹姆斯,我们面对着一种
已出现并正在发挥作用的力量
We have the opportunity
to study it,
to learn from it, to teach it
its limitations.
我们有机会来学习,学习它,
教它们什么是它们的极限
We can, in a word,
educate it.
我们能,就是说,教育它
You said you called.
你说过你呼叫了
We can try the blue, of course,
but they'd only readapt again.
我们可以郁闷,当然可以,
但它们会再次适应的
So we have to consider
other alternatives.
因此我们得确认其他的选择
You mean you didn't call?
你是说你没呼叫?
It is absolutely vital that
we give them the opportunity
to try their strength
against ours,
我们给它们机会来试试它们对付
我们的强项,这是非常重要的
and learn from its consequences.
和学习它的后果
I'm gonna call in, hubbs.
我要去呼叫他们,哈布斯
And I'm gonna tell them not only
to take that girl out of here,
而且我打算告诉他们
不止要带那女孩离开这里
I'm gonna tell them to take me
out of here too.
我打算跟他们说我也要离开这里
You wanna call?
你想呼叫他们?
You're just as fascinated
by this challenge as I am.
你和我一样,
对这个挑战感到着迷
Ah!
啊!
We're cut off.
我们被切断连接了
Then our success
will be all the sweeter.
然后我们会更有成就感
Sunday, one o'clock,
星期天,一点
the battle is on,
战争即将爆发,
lesko is preparing
the counteraction
莱斯科正准备反抗
I have indicated.
我已经指出来了
The air conditioner
is being adjusted
to take account
of the temperature rise.
考虑到温度的上升,
空调一直在调整
Human beings can exist
in temperatures of 120 degrees
or higher.
人类能够在120华氏度
或者在更高的情况下生存
But our computer shuts down
at 90.
但我们的计算机
在90华氏度时就关机了
Kendra?
坎多拉?
You wanna see
what we're doing?
你想看看我们在做什么吗?
Come on, I'll show you,
it's interesting.
来吧,我展示给你看,很有趣的
The name of the game today
is king of the hill.
今天的游戏就叫做"山丘之王"
You see over there?
你看到了吗?
Now we wanna knock them down
before they burn us out, okay?
现在我们要在它们把我们
给烧了之前把它们炸下来,好吗?
What's that?
那是什么?
White sound.
白声
That's every sound in the world
all pushed together
世界上所有的声音
都被挤到一块儿去了
to make one really
terrific noise
以制造一个超大的噪音
which we're broadcasting
to those mounds out there.
我们要向外面的那些土丘播放
And that's what it looks like
as we send it out.
看起来就像是
我们把他送出去的一样
Okay?
好了吗?
Now when that sound
gets out to those mounds,
当那些声音传过那些土丘时,
it bounces right back here
and winds up down there.
它会反弹回来,
风也会吹到那里
Good.
Something's missing.
很好,错过了一些东西
One of the sounds we sent out
didn't come back.
我们发送出去的一个声音
没有反射回来
Now let's just see if we can
find out what that sound is.
现在我们来找找那是什么声音吧
There it is.
就是这个了
Now that's the sound we're gonna
broadcast to those mounds.
这就是我们打算向
那些土丘播放的声音
And when we do, interesting
things better happen.
当我们动手时,
最好要有些有趣的现象
If you think that's loud for us
如果你觉得那太大声了,
think about how those ants
are gonna feel.
想想那些蚂蚁会有什么感觉
That'll do it.
开始动手了
They're going crazy.
它们快要发疯了
James?
詹姆斯?
Damn air conditioner.
该死的空调
I'm afraid I'm feeling rather-
ow!
恐怕我感觉很...喔!
It's on fire.
Get away from it.
着火了,快离开那儿
Get out of the way.
走开
I just... I can't believe it.
我只是...我不能相信
To know our plans,
知道我们的计划,
our strength,
our weaknesses.
我们的强项,我们的弱点
Even the one machine
that everything else depends on.
甚至是机器所依靠的一切条件
How could they know?
它们怎么知道的?
This is impossible.
那不可能
They knew.
它们知道了
I am choosing one of
my less painful moments
to record these notes.
我选择在没那么
痛苦的时候来记笔记
Our equipment
only functions now
for a few hours at night.
我们的设备仅在夜间的
短短几个小时内起作用
Lesko believes
we're being allowed this time
for some purpose.
莱斯科相信我们是因某些目的
而被允许在夜间工作的
A hypothesis, I do not share.
有个假说,我还没说
If this were so
it would raise questions
如果真是这样的话,
那问题就多了
I had not considered.
我还没有确认
"Transfer to..."
转移至...
"Nag tape unit three."
第三单位磁带
"Go straight six units."
推进六个单位
"Right 120 degrees"
向右120度
"four units."
四个单位
"Right 60 degrees"
向右60度
"four units."
四个单位
"Right 120 degrees"
向右120度
"six units."
四个单位
What are you doing?
你在干什么?
I'm doing something my way.
我在以我的形式行事
I'm sending a message
to the ants.
我正在向蚂蚁发送信息
Yes, I've been thinking
about that.
是的,我一直在想
The conditioning process
must be working.
过程条件一定起作用了
But they're not all affected
as yet.
但它们并非全部都被影响到了
They must be informed
of their losses
and their suffering
它们一定了解到了
它们的损失和所遭受的
so they can draw
the appropriate conclusions.
所以它们能得出适当的结论了
Where is your message?
你的信息呢?
On the plotter.
在绘图机上
This is no message.
什么也没有
Mathematics is
the universal language
among intelligent creatures.
数学是聪明的动物
之间的宇宙语言
If there's an intelligence there
如果有理解力的话
I want it to know
there's an intelligence here.
我要它知道这里
有智力的存在
Go away.
走开
Please go away.
请走开
Hubbs: We're reviewing data.
哈布斯:我们正在审查数据
Previous analysis show...
之前的解析表明...
Do you wanna drink this?
Analysis...
-你想喝这个吗?
-解析...
What?
什么?
Clear, they failed to achieve
a...
完成了,它们的计划失败了,而且...
They will learn
we've made up our mind.
它们会认识到我们已下定决心
How did they know?
它们怎么知道的?怎么知道的?
You!
因为你!
Kendra: Jim! Jim!
坎德拉:吉姆!吉姆!
Jim: What's going on
back there?
吉姆:后面发生了什么事?
Hubbs. Hubbs.
Come on, come on.
哈布斯,哈布斯,振作起来,快点
I am not helpless,
I will not be humiliated.
我不是没用的人,我不会被羞辱
Got him!
抓住他!
I'm sorry.
很抱歉
Come on, come on.
快点,快点
Could you hold me
for a minute?
你能抱住我一会儿吗?
James?
詹姆斯?
If I was irrational during
the heat of the day,
如果我在大热天下不理智的话,
I apologize.
我道歉
Why don't they kill us?
它们怎么不杀了我们?
Why roast us in here all day,
dare us to come out at night?
为什么一整天都要在这烤我们?
怂恿我们在晚上跑出去么?
Why play these games?
为什么这么玩我们?
What do they want?
它们到底要什么?
I've been thinking about
specialization
among certain insects.
我一直在想某些昆虫的特化
Take it easy.
放松点
Try to get some sleep.
试着睡下吧
In every ant colony...
在每个蚁群...
Workers, winged males
and the queen.
工蚁,雄蚁和蚁后
Ants are organized
by the queen.
蚂群是由蚁后所组织的
Keeping her alive.
保住她的性命
She's the heart and soul
of their lives.
她是它们的核心与灵魂
She's at the centre.
It is she who speaks.
她就在中心,
这就是她所说的
If she died,
如果她死了,
discipline, organization
would crumble.
再有纪律的组织也会瓦解
The war's over, hubbs.
战争结束了,哈布斯
They have the power.
它们有能力
Only hope now is if they answer
our message in the morning.
现在只能祈祷它们能
在明早回复我们的信息
Convince them
we're worth keeping alive.
让它们相信我们活着会更有价值
I think I could locate the queen
and kill her.
我想我能锁定蚁后然后干掉她
Lock the tracker onto her voice
when she speaks.
当她说话时锁定她声音的轨道
What makes you think
she'd speak to you?
是什么让你觉得她会和你对话?
What is it?
那是什么?
Th-the-the-lights.
灯...灯...灯光
Ha-ha, it's just a...
哈哈,只不过是...
Bare in mind
we still have our hard suits.
要记住我们还有些坚硬的外套
Yeah, two of them.
对啊,两套
They're sending back my message.
它们正在回复我们的信息
Hubbs, there's more.
哈布斯,这里还有
What does it mean?
这是什么意思?
What the hell does it mean?
这他妈的是什么意思?
A circle with a dot.
一个圆圈和一个圆点
Now I know how a rat feels
in a maze.
现在我知道老鼠是
因什么而感到困惑的了
Rats in a maze.
困惑的老鼠
It's almost like
a controlled experiment
in which we are the subjects.
这很像是一个
以我们为实验对象的对照实验
Find out which rat
is the smartest.
找出哪只老鼠最聪明
The strongest.
哪只最强
An intelligence test.
这是个智力测验
Could the circle be this place?
圆圈就是这地方吗?
And what does the dot represent?
那圆点代表什么?
Could the dot be a person?
圆点就是一个人吗?
Someone they want.
它们想要某些人
Who could they want?
它们想要谁?
They want somebody?
它们想要某人?
I think so.
我是这么想的
But why would they want
somebody?
但它们为什么想要某人?
To talk to them.
为了跟它们对话
You mean they...
你是说它们...
They might be angry at someone
who did them some harm?
它们可能是对某些
对它们造成伤害的人感到愤怒?
What would they do
with that person?
它们会对那个人做什么?
I don't know.
我不知道
Would they let the others
go free?
它们会放其他人走吗?
James.
詹姆斯
Come here.
过来
I believe
I've located the queen.
我相信我已经锁定蚁后了
She's in there.
她就在那里
♪ Oh, sweet to walk ♪
♪ In the pilgrims way ♪
♪ Leaning on
the everlasting arms ♪
♪ Oh, how bright the path ♪
♪ Grows from day to day ♪
♪ Leaning on the everla- ♪
Where are the grenades?
手榴弹在哪?
Used up when you destroyed
the towers.
在你摧毁那些塔时要用完
All of them?
全都要?
Then we must devise
something else.
然后我们一定能想出别的办法
James, please I...
詹姆斯,求你了,我...
My boots I...
我的长筒靴...我...
Would you please,
I can't...
求你了,我不能...
You're gonna walk out of here?
你想走出这里?
Trek miles through the desert?
跋涉几英里以穿越沙漠吗?
Destroy a colony full of
poisonous ants
and a deadly queen?
摧毁一个满是毒蚂蚁和
致命的蚁后的蚁群么?
You can't even
get your boots on.
你的长筒靴连踏进去都不行
Come on, Hubbs, sit down.
算了吧,哈布斯,坐下
What we're gonna do
is send another message.
我们需要做的是
再发另一条消息
You must go!
你必须得去!
You must show them
we will not...
你必须向它们表示,我们不会...
Man will not give in.
人类不会投降的
Did I tell you I figured out
their first message?
我有跟你说过
我想出了它们的第一条信息吗?
The dot is you.
那圆点就是你
They want you.
它们想要的是你
And they shall soon have me.
然后它们不久后也会抓到我
I'm sorry, Hubbs,
很抱歉,哈布斯
it's not gonna happen your way.
不会像你想的那样发生的
Kendra.
坎多拉
Stop!
She's there.
停下!她在那儿
That hill, the queen.
那山丘,蚁后
Hubbs, you can't do it.
Now come on, come on!
哈布斯,你不能这么做,
现在算了吧,算了!
Queen!
蚁后!
Hubbs!
哈布斯!
Goddamn you.
你们这帮混蛋!
Hubbs!
哈布斯!
I would still like
to believe that given time
we could have come
to an understanding.
我还是愿意相信
在当时我们能达成谅解
Some rational accommodation
of interests,
some agreement.
理解宽容的利害关系,一些协定
But that's not the way
it's going to be.
但那不会是
接下来即将发生的事
I've made some calculations
about their rate of expansion
我已经盘算了它们的扩张程度
using their intelligence and
their powers of organization,
利用它们的智力和组织的力量
and their network
of communications,
还有它们的通讯网络
their poisons.
它们的毒素
Their ability to adapt
genetically.
它们适应环境的能力的基因
I believe that after
this test run now
我相信在这次测试运行之后
they'll move rather quickly
into desert areas.
它们会更快的移动至沙漠地区
Taking over the countryside
first
先把农村给占领了
then laying siege to towns
and cities.
然后围攻市镇和城市
I believe they will learn
as they advance,
我相信它们会在前进时学习
anticipating our moves and
continue to stay a move ahead.
预料我们的动作并继续走在前头
We have only one chance,
我们只有一个机会,
the counter attack
suggested by doctor Hubbs.
反攻是哈布斯博士提议的
A direct assault
on their queen.
对它们的蚁后
进行一次直接的打击
Jesus, I wish it wasn't me.
天哪,我希望那不是你
There you are.
你在那里
They wanted...
它们想要...
Us.
我们
We knew then,
we were being changed
我们知道后,
我们就被改变了
and made part of their world.
然后成了它们世界的一部分
We didn't know
for what purpose.
我们不知道它们的目的是什么
But we knew we would be told.
但我们知道,会有人告诉我们的